THUNDER GATE
FIVE YEARS AGO
（人々のざわめき）
SEPTEMBER 12, 2034
TEN YEARS SINCE THE CALAMITY
Five years ago,
（キルコ）５年前
we made our living
in the Electro-Kart Racing industry.
僕らは電動カートレースの
興行を生業にしていた
TEAM FUNAYAMA - KIRIKO TAKEHAYA
Come on, Ozaki!
（観客１）頼むぞ 尾崎！
（エンジン音）
（観客２）片山！
Katayama!
Kiriko!
（観客３）桐子きりこちゃーん！
（桐子）ん…
（観客たちの歓声）
（春希はるきの息切れ）
-Come back!
-Stop there!
（春希）待て！
（ケン）待て オラッ！
（詐欺師）ハッ！
（衝撃音）
（レーサー１）ハッ！ 竹早たけはやか？
Takehaya?
Damn it.
クソッ！
（春希）ハアハア… ハア… ハア
（ケン）深追いするな　春希！
Don't chase them too far! Haruki!
（レーサー２）ハッ！
ふっ…
（衝撃音）
ぐわっ…
（詐欺師１･２）
ハア… ハア… ハア…
Let's get the hell outta here.
早く 逃げようぜ
いや コイツには顔を見られた
But that little brat has seen our faces.
ハッ…　うっ！
（近づく足音）
What?
え？
Looks like you've been looking after
our young lad, huh?
（ロビン）ウチの若いもんが
随分 世話になってる
みたいじゃないか
Robin!
These guys have been making fake tickets!
ロビン！ コイツらニセの車券を
作ってやがったんだ
（詐欺師２）ううっ… うう
うあああーっ！
♪～
TENGOKU-DAIMAKYO
～♪
う… うう
Did you think you could kill me
with a tiny scrap of metal?
（ロビン）そんな金属片で
俺を殺せると思ったのかよ！
Haruki, when you fight your enemies,
you don't need to stare into their eyes.
春希 ケンカする時は
相手から目をそらしてもいいんだ
Glaring is just something cowards do
相手の目をにらむなんてのは
when they want to get away
with only intimidating their opponents.
威嚇だけで事なきを得ようって
チキンがやることだ
Avoid the eyes,
and concentrate on the collar instead.
目をそらして相手の襟を見な
Then focus on the ground,
check how it feels beneath your feet.
それから地面 足の裏で
立っている感触を確かめろ
（足音）
（春希）ん…
Those who do nothing
but look at their opponents, lose.
ケンカは相手しか
見えなくなってるヤツが負ける
Let's hand these guys over to the boss.
コイツらは上のもんに引き渡す
Nice going, Haruki.
春希 お前の手柄だ
If you want something, just ask me.
なんか欲しいもんがあったら言え
はあっ！
（足音）
We're back!
（春希）ただいま！
What meat is that?
それ なんの肉？
Monkey, crow and mouse. I think.
（蘭らん）猿と… カラスとネズミかな
Wow, cool jacket!
あれ そのジャンパー！
Robin gave it to me.
ロビンにもらった！
ハハッ ちょっとでかいよな
It's a little baggy.
He'll grow into it quickly, though!
すぐ ちょうどよくなるよ
Now I want something too.
へ～ いいな～ 私もなんか欲しい
How about trousers?
Bet they'll fit if you cut them in half.
じゃ ズボンでももらえば
半分に切れば履けるだろ
なっ！ そんなに足短くないわ！
My legs are not that short!
（一同の笑い）
（桐子）おなかすいた～
I'm hungry.
（ケン）ん？
（春希）姉ちゃん おかえり！
Sis, you're back!
（ケン）ううっ…
Where did you finish?
（春希）何着だった？
Didn't you see? I was disqualified.
I fell out of my kart.
見てなかったの？ 落車して棄権
What? Did you hurt yourself?
（３人）えっ！
ケガは？
No, I'm okay.
The other drivers went around me.
後続の人がよけてくれたから平気
Right, Doc?
ね 先生
That's so dangerous.
You gotta be more careful!
（春希）
危ない！ マジで気をつけろよ！
You really should drive more safely.
（医者）本当に気をつけた方がいい
I get it, I get it.
分かった 分かった
REPORTS OF SPECTATORS
GOING MISSING
Oh, yeah, Kiriko.
あ そうだ 桐子ちゃん　へっ…
I attached a flash to my camera.
私のカメラに
フラッシュ付いたんだよ
Let's take some new photos to sell.
新しいブロマイド
作って売ろうよ フフッ
Take one of me and Doc, then.
じゃあ 先生と１枚撮ってよ
I'm good, thanks.
僕はいいよ
Ready!
撮るよー
（蘭）えへへ
（医者）もう行くよ
-Time to go.
-Okay.
うん ありがとう 先生
Thanks, Doc.
Haruki, I heard the doc
is researching "Man-eaters,"
春希 あの医者
隠れて人食いの研究したり
and even experimenting on humans.
人体実験してるって話だぜ
What?
ええっ！
Robin's investigating at the moment.
（ケン）今 ロビンが調べてる
But it'd be better if Kiriko
didn't get too close to him.
あんまり桐子ちゃんを
近づけないほうがいいぞ
はあ…
CURRENTLY IN USE
BY FUNAYAMA ORPHANAGE
KIRIKO AND HARUKI TAKEHAYA
Haruki, aren't you cold?
（桐子）春希 寒くない？
（春希）うん 姉ちゃんは？
No, you?
Freezing.
寒い
（春希）
えっ？ じゃあこっち入る？
Wanna get in here?
うわっ！ ほ… 本当に入るの？
You're actually getting in?
（複数の足音）
（桐子･春希）ん？
What's happening?
（春希）どうしたの？
There's a Man-eater in the third district!
３丁目に人食いが出た！
It's not coming this way,
so go back to sleep.
こっちには来させねーから
気にせず寝てろ！
-Let's go, Robin!
-Coming!
（男１）行くぞ ロビン！
（ロビン）はい！
（春希）んっ…
Are you going?
行くの？
It's okay, I have the gun that I made,
大丈夫！ 僕の作った銃もあるし
and I want to be helpful to Robin.
ロビンの役に立ちたいんだ！
ん…
If I think about those days…
（キルコ）
思えばこの頃が 僕にとっての
they seem like heaven to me now.
“天国〟だったのかもしれない
KIRIKO AND HARUKI
（発射音）
Not bad.
（お兄）すげえじゃん
（春希）あ…
You killed a Man-eater
with that weapon last week?
先週 その武器で
人食い退治したんだって？
Yeah.
うん…
遊びでやってんじゃねえ
危ねえから来んなつっただろ！
I'm not playing around!
I told you not to come. It's dangerous!
I made Robin angry, though.
…って怒られたよ
Ten years ago, Robin had a sister my age.
ロビンは10年前の大災害で
（子供たちの笑い声）
He lost her in the Great Disaster.
僕と同じ歳の妹を亡くしてるんだ
Since then, he's been overprotective.
だから… 何て言うかちょっと
過保護なんだよね
ハッ！ あっと 今 何時？
Wait! What time is it?
Which watch is right again?
（妹）えーっと
合ってる時計はどれかいなあ…
-That one.
-Twenty after two.
これだ
おっ ２時20分
I have to go! Sis's race starts at three!
（春希）いかん！
３時から姉ちゃんのレースだ
See you later!
またねー！
Robin might be overprotective,
（お兄）
ロビンは過保護かもしれないけど
アイツはシスコンだね
but that guy is obsessed with his sister.
そだねー
Right?
SEPTEMBER 20, 2034
TEN YEARS SINCE THE CALAMITY
（観客たちの歓声）
（エンジン音）
Okay, just made it.
（春希）よし 間に合った…
（シャッターを踏む音）
ん？
うわっ！ 誰か！
Help!
There's a Man-eater
at the end of the track!
コースの終盤に 人食いがいる！
（観客たちの歓声）
It can turn invisible,
same as the one before!
この前と同じ 透明になるやつ
（観客１）桐ちゃーん！
（観客２）がんばれ！
（エンジン音･歓声）
All karts are off at once!
（実況）さあ 各車一斉に
スタートしていきました
What kind of race will it be today?
今日は一体 どんなレースが
待っているのか！
Sis.
姉ちゃん…　くっ
（春希）
人食いが入っていったアーケードに
ハア ハア ハア ハア…
The Man-eater's gone into the arcade.
It's probably seven or eight minutes
until the karts get there.
カートが来るまで
７～８分はあるはずだ
I'll drive it away.
僕が追い払う
I know I can do it.
僕がやるんだ！
After the long straight,
（実況）長い直線を終え
第２コーナーを曲がったのは
８番 ３番 ４番 うわーっと
karts eight, three and four
round the second corner.
It's a crash for two and five,
a spin that will set them way back!
５番 ２番がここでスピン！
大きく遅れた！
The rest are off towards Sensoji.
集団はそのまま浅草寺へ
Number four, Takehaya,
you pulled that off well!
４番 竹早 上手く引き剥がした！
-Goddamn it!
-Nice one, Kiriko!
桐子ちゃん いいぞお！
Where is it?
（春希）どこだ？
Has it left the course?
コースから出たのか…？
Got it!
そこか！
Unbelievable, it barely hurt it.
ビックリするほど効いてない…
（片山）うっ…
うわっ！
（春希）フウ… フウ…
フウ… フウ…
（深呼吸）
はっ！
はああっ！
（人食いのうめき声）
Finally, got a hit.
（春希）やった 手応えが… うわあ
うわあ！ うわ…
ううっ…
My arm!
手が！
（うめき声）
Let me go!
放せっ… うう…
うわあー！
（おびえる声）
It's eating me.
食われる！
うわあーっ！
Robin, help me!
助けて ロビン！
Takehaya's in the lead,
（実況）先頭４番 竹早
exiting the third corner
towards the arcade.
第３コーナーを抜けてアーケードへ
They'll be momentarily out of sight.
さて ここからしばらく
放送席からも追えなくなります
The Asakusa Race Association
ただいま 浅草レース会では
全コースに中継カメラの…
is in the process of arranging for cameras
to be installed throughout the course.
（桐子）ハッ！
If you can offer such a service,
then by all means, please get in touch.
（レーサー）ん？ なんだ？
Stop! There's a Man-eater!
Call the race off!
（桐子）止まれ！ 人食いが出た
レースは無効だ！
Go back and tell the headquarters.
戻って本部に知らせろ
Okay.
（レーサー）おっ おう
（奇妙な音）
ハッ！
Haruki?
春希…！
Haruki!
春希ーっ！
うっ…
うっ
（人食いのうめき声）
（桐子）ううっ… う…
Give him back.
かえ… せ…
Let him go!
春希を… 返せーっ！
ハア… ハア… ハア…
ハッ！
Haru… No.
う… うそ…
It can't be.
やだ…
あ… ああ…
（むせび泣く声）
ひい… 誰か… 誰か早く…
Somebody! Anybody, quickly!
Help!
誰かーっ！
（春希）姉… ちゃん… だ
（桐子の泣き声）
Sis…
She's so close.
近い… なあ…
Sis…
ね… ちゃ…
（発砲音）
CURRENTLY IN USE
BY FUNAYAMA ORPHANAGE
Everyone…
（春希）みんな…
Sis?
姉ちゃん…
My head…
頭…
It's so hot.
熱い…
Sis.
姉… ちゃん…
（発砲音）
ん…
Sis?
姉ちゃん？
ん…？
あ…
うわっ！ 姉ちゃん！
Sis!
（キルコ）ハッ！ ハア… ハア…
（女性）ハア… ハッ
ハッ…
竹早さんの意識が戻りました！
Takehaya has regained consciousness!
Apparently,
there's another Man-eater in the area,
（患者１）また人食いが出たってよ
and a child is dead.
子供が１人 亡くなったと
That's horrifying.
（患者２）ムゴいなあ…
Excuse me.
あの… ハッ…
あ… えっ え…
（患者１･２）ん？
Why…
（キルコ）あれ…
あ… ハッ！
Si-- Sis?
ね…
姉ちゃん？ わあっ！
うっ… わあっ！
Me?
僕？
The patient, she--
（キルコ）うわー！
（女性）３０１の…
（男性）ん？
あ…！ ああ… ああ…
Takehaya!
ああ… ああ… ああ…！
（女性）竹早さん！
You shouldn't be walking yet!
歩くのは まだ無理よ！
Stop! I'm Haruki!
うるさい！ 僕は春希だ！
-Where's Sis?
-Get a tranquilizer!
（キルコ）姉ちゃんどこ！
姉ちゃんに会いたい！
（男性１）鎮静剤！
（男性２）はい
-Going!
-I want my sister! Sis!
うう… 姉ちゃん… 姉ちゃーん！
（男性１）
落ち着いて ああ… ね
-You need to calm down.
-Sis! Sis!
I think that
the shock of her brother's death
（女性）恐らく
弟を死なせてしまったショックから
（キルコ）う… ハア…
has led her to believe
that she is her brother.
自分を弟だと
思い込んでいるようです
The poor girl.
（男性１）かわいそうに
The doctor.
（キルコ）医者は…？
（男性１）ん？
What did the doctor do?
（キルコ）あの医者が何かしたんだ
He must know what happened.
アイツなら分かる
Where's the doctor?
医者はどこだ！
After giving you both medical attention,
the doctor left town.
先生はあなたたちの治療をした後
この町を去りました
ハッ…
You were both brought here
on the verge of death.
（女性）あなたたち姉弟は
２人とも瀕死の状態で担ぎ込まれた
SURGERY IN PROGRESS
What happened to your brother
is incredibly upsetting,
弟さんのことは残念だったけど
どういう治療をしたにせよ
but no matter what treatment we used,
先生がいなければ
２人とも死んでいたと思います
without the doctor,
I believe you would both be dead.
ハッ… ハア…
--SOJI HOSPITAL
I don't understand.
（キルコ）分からない…
Last time I saw her,
最後に見た姉ちゃんは
she was crying, but definitely alive.
泣いてたけど ちゃんと生きてた
Was she eaten by the Man-eater?
あの後 姉ちゃんも
人食いにやられちゃったのかな…
One thing is undeniable.
確かなことは
自分が春希だということ
I am definitely still Haruki.
The proof of that
その証拠に 確実に襲ってくる
姉を失った悲しみ
is the sorrow splintering through me
at the news of my sister's death,
and the occasional faint solace
そして 時折もたげる
of having inherited
the body of someone I love.
好きな女の体を手に入れた
薄暗い喜び
By the time my sister's wounds had healed,
and I could start to move her body again,
姉ちゃんの体のケガが癒え
ある程度動けるようになった頃には
nearly four months had passed.
入院から４ヵ月近く経っていた
Robin must be investigating
what that doctor was up to.
ロビンは医者の裏の顔を
探ってたはずだ
I'm sure he will be able to figure it out.
ロビンならきっと調べられる
He'll be able to tell me
why I have become my sister,
どうして僕が
姉ちゃんになっているのか
and why she had to die.
なんで姉ちゃんが死んじゃったのか
ASAKUSA RACE ASSOCIATION
HEADQUARTERS
Excuse me.
（キルコ）すみません
（レース会の男）ん？
I'm hoping to see Robin Inazaki
from the Asakusa Race Association--
浅草レース会の稲崎いなざき露敏ろびんに
会いたいんですけど
ああ そりゃ無理だなあ…
That's not possible.
Sometime around September last year,
ロビンは去年の９月頃だったか
I'm pretty sure he was murdered.
たぶん 殺されちまってるよ
ハッ…
ハアハア…
There was an increase in disappearances
around here last year.
（レース会の男）
去年この辺で失踪事件が増えて
ハア… ハア… ハア…
Seems he got tangled up
in trying to investigate.
それ絡みで犯人を
調査してたらしいが
Then, just like that,
he ended up disappearing too.
結局 本人もそのまま消えちまった
ハア… ハア… ハア…
ハアハア… うっ… ハア
Ken! Ran!
ケン！ 蘭！
Director!
園長！
Anyone!
みんなっ！
ハア… ハア…
ハッ…
Please! What happened to
the orphanage that was here?
すみません！
こ… ここにあった船山ふなやま孤児院は？
-It was moved elsewhere.
-What?
（通行人）どこか よそへ行ったよ
え…
（通行人）稼ぎ頭だったレーサーが
事故で亡くなったり
Their highest earning racer died…
REPORTS OF SPECTATORS
GOING MISSING
リーダー格の子が行方不明とかで
…and the leader went missing.
は… ああ…
I expect with all the bad luck,
they gave up on this town.
いろいろ不幸が重なって
この町でやっていけく
なったんだろうねえ
（ドアが開く音）
（ドアが閉まる音）
（ベットに倒れ込む音）
Sis.
姉ちゃん…
Robin.
ロビン… うう…
うっ…
（レース会の男）
結局 本人もそのまま消えちまった
Then, just like that,
he ended up disappearing too.
The leader went missing.
（通行人）
リーダー格の子が行方不明とかで
ハッ！
行方不明？ 消えちまった？
"Missing"?
"Disappeared"?
There isn't actually any proof
that Robin is dead.
まだロビンが死んだっていう
確証がないじゃないか！
あ…
There's no way Robin can be dead.
ロビンが死ぬわけない…
ハア…
He must be alive somewhere.
絶対どこかで生きてる！ ハッ…
The doctor.
医者だ…
The doctor has the answer to everything.
医者が全部知ってる！
Where Robin is, why my sister is dead
ロビンの行方も
姉ちゃんが死んだ理由も…
うう… うっ…
and why I'm living inside her body!
僕が姉ちゃんになって
生きてる理由も！
TRIP GUARD
PROTECTION FROM WILD ANIMALS,
BANDITS AND MAN-EATERS - KIRUKO
After that, I lived in various towns,
searching for the two of them,
（キルコ）それから
２人を探して いろんな街に住み
accepting requests,
and doing everything by myself.
依頼をこなし １人で何でも
できるようになって
Four years later, I met you in Nakano.
それから４年ほどして
中野で君と出会ったんだよ
DO NOT ENTER
It's the first time I've told anyone that.
こんな話を人にしたのは初めてだ
I want to check something with you.
（マル）１つ確認したいんだけど…
Would it be better
if I stopped calling you "Sis"?
お姉ちゃん… って
呼ばないほうがよかったかな
That?
そこ？
Don't worry about it.
いや いいよ
You've been calling me that for a month,
pretty sure we're both used to it now.
もう１ヵ月近く呼ばれてるし
お互い慣れてるでしょ
Well, there you go.
You'll have to think of me as a man now.
ま そういうワケなので
僕のことは男だと思っておいて
I can't wrap my mind around it
just like that!
そんな急にムリだよ…
（マル）ん… ん
Anyway,
you're getting pretty good looking.
君 ちょっといないくらい
美少年だから
I'm sure you'll meet someone
more appropriate soon.
すぐふさわしい相手見つかるって
I won't find a girl
I get along with this well.
こんな気が合う女の人
見つかんないよ
That's because we're both guys.
それは頭が男同士だから
So the photo of Jane Inamura, right?
（マル）
写真の… 稲村ジェーンだっけ？
It's Robin Inazaki.
稲崎ロビンね
What do you think about him?
（マル）
その人のことはどう思ってるの？
Well,
そうだな…
we grew up in the same house,
so I guess he's like family.
ずっと同じ家で育ったから
家族みたいなもんだし
But he's also a close friend.
親友でもあるし
I suppose I admire him.
憧れてもいたよ
（マル）ん～…
Because we're both guys! I look up to him.
だから！ 同性としてだよ！
You still don't get it, do you?
君 まだ混乱してるよね
What do you expect
when you tell someone something like that?
こんなフラれ方したら
そりゃ混乱もするよ！
はあー
Maybe a good night's sleep
will sort your head out.
１回寝て 頭を整理しなよ
Fine.
（マル）そうする
起きたらこの話も夢になってるかも
Maybe when I wake up
this will all turn out to be a dream.
（船客１）うわあ！
What now? What's the racket for?
何よっ うるさいな！
わ… わあっ！
What is it?
（キルコ）どうした！
There was a huge fish outside the window.
窓の外にでっかい魚がいたんだよ！
A fish?
魚？
The window is wet,
even though it's not raining.
確かに 雨も降っていないのに
窓の外が濡れてる
Strange.
妙だな
Maru, go and tell the captain
to keep an eye--
マル 一応警戒だ
船長に…
（マル･船客１）わっ わっ…
A Man-eater.
人食いだ
♪～
～♪
（クク）ん… ん…っと
ンフ…
Is it a baby?
（クク）これ 赤ちゃん？
Can I have it?
この絵 僕にちょうだいよ
I promised to give this one to Tokio.
You can have the next.
（コナ）これは トキオにあげる
約束だから この次ね
Sounds good to me!
やった！ コナの絵はヘンでいいね
I like your weird drawing.
（足音）
（コナ）フッ… ヘンかな？
You think it's weird?
ヘンだよ
だってほんとの赤ちゃんは…
Obviously! Proper babies--
うわあ！ ひゃあ
Climbing on tables is forbidden, Kuku.
（教師ロボット）こらククくん
テーブルに乗ってはいけません！
Stop annoying Kona and come with me.
（トキオ）ほらクク！
コナの邪魔になるからあっち行くよ
うわあ… おっと…
Hey--
If you're going to be nasty about them,
then stop asking for Kona's drawings!
君 コナの絵にケチつけるなら
欲しがるなよ
I was saying they were good!
（クク）ほめてたんだよー
Besides, I've seen one. A real baby.
それに僕見たもん　本物の赤ちゃん
えっ…
Real babies don't have faces.
本物の赤ちゃんには 顔がないんだ
フフッ
Want to go and see it?
トキオも見に行く？